Guide to the Faculty Reference Collection, 1972-2000
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Faculty Reference collection 1972-2000
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
1.3 Linear Feet 1300 Items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Faculty Reference Collection were received by the University Archives as a transfer in The Faculty Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources..
Collection Overview
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, registers, handbooks, newsletters, flyers, news clippings, and other printed and manuscript material concerning the activities of faculty, services for active and emeriti faculty, relations between the faculty and students and the faculty and the administration, salaries, and other matters. The bulk dates of the material are 1960-1990. The materials include a list of women faculty (1936-1952), and copies of faculty newsletters and faculty handbooks. Cataloged copies of the handbooks and newsletters are available.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
College teachers -- North Carolina -- Durham
College teachers -- Retirement -- North Carolina -- Durham
Duke University -- Faculty
Duke University -- Faculty -- Handbooks, manuals, etc
Duke University -- Faculty -- Officials and employees -- Salaries, etc
Duke University -- Faculty -- Periodicals
Related Material
Academic Council Records, 1954-2000
Duke University Archives
Black History at Duke Reference Collection, 1948-2001 and undated
Duke University Archives
Duke University Faculty. Records, 1911-
Duke University Archives
Faculty Club of Duke University Records, 1918-1976
Duke University Archives
Detailed Description of Collection
- Container List
  - Academic Freedom, 1978-
  - Ad hoc committee on faculty referendum, 1970-1971
  - American Association of University Professors, Duke chapter, 1952-1983
  - Appointments and promotions, clippings, circa 1985-1998
  - Committee on retirement housing, 1968-1971
  - Distinguished professors
    - Clippings
    - Lists, 1967-
    - Memoranda, circa 1967
    - News Releases, 1972-
  - Duke Faculty Committee for Alternatives to Nuclear Power, 1979
  - Faculty Associates Program, 1995-1996
  - Faculty Christmas Party/Holiday Party
  - Faculty Club, 1952-1971
  - Faculty Commons, 1984-1993
  - Faculty couples, 2001
  - Faculty emeriti [1940s], 1963-1996
  - Faculty and Staff Emeriti Lists, circa 1972-2001
  - Faculty health clinic, [1970]
  - Faculty home sites, 1953-1966
  - Faculty lecture series, 1992
  - Faculty Newsletter Committee, 1965-1969
  - Faculty Newsletter, clippings, 1993
  - Faculty publications, 1950
  - Faculty salaries, circa 1947-2000
  - Faculty-student relations, 1983-2000
  - Governance, 1982
  - National Association of Scholars (NAS), circa 1990-1996
  - NAS: Duke Association of Scholars, circa 1993-1998
  - Ombudsman, 1984-
  - Teaching and teaching assistants
  - Tenure
  - Women faculty, 1952-2000
  - Distinguished Professors, Duke University, 1961, 1965, 1968, 1973, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Distinguished Professors, Duke University, 1984, 1991
  - Faculty Handbook, 1968, 1969
  - Faculty Handbook, 1982, 1987
  - Faculty Newsletter, 1959-1960, 1966-1969